<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Neil Ding]]></title>
  <link href="http://gxding.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://gxding.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-04-04T10:27:13-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://gxding.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Neil Ding]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[bbbear444@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[first expose to test]]></title>
    <link href="http://gxding.com/blog/2015/04/26/first-expose-to-test/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-26T16:50:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://gxding.com/blog/2015/04/26/first-expose-to-test</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have seen quite a lot of talking about test, and tried a little RSpec when learning Ruby on Rails years ago. But I don&rsquo;t really get myself dig into the testing world. Today is Sunday, it&rsquo;s a sudden that come to my mind that maybe I should spend some time figure it out.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s a sad fact that the company I am working never encourage writing test for project. It relays a lot on human QA. Well that&rsquo;s not bad in some sense. But apparently we can be more efficient and get less bug if we adopt automated test. There seems to be architecture change in term of development. I found it a good chance to add test to the new architecture.</p>

<p>I just spend an afternoon make the test working for the <a href="https://github.com/GingerBear/nba-daily">nba-daily project</a> that I have worked months ago. It has similar idea behind the company project, which proxying site to a better UI. In the mind, the test should be to pretty simple, namely, going to a page, checking that page contains what we need, going to another page, checking again.</p>

<p>Check element is pretty common in testing. Most test framework and assert library should already taken then cared. The only thing is to requesting page. Obviously we cannot use node&rsquo;s plane http request module because if the real project, the request has to maintain the cookie and session. Normally cookie and session is handled by browser, so my first head to find those browser testing tools. It turns out that there is thing called Selenium, which can opens up local or remote browser, and use the browser to make the request. It can use different web driver to drive different browser. I tried the <code>chai-webdriver</code> and chrome driver, it works, but it won&rsquo;t work on the Travis CI, which doesn&rsquo;t have a browser GUI. To make Travis work, we need to use remote browser on virtual machine. I know that I have pay to use that.</p>

<p>Then it come up another solution, PhantomJS. It call itself <code>headless WebKit</code>. It&rsquo;s hard to understand what is headless. But to my understanding, it&rsquo;s browser without GUI, and can be fully controlled by JavaScript (comparing to real browsers that expose limited API). And fortunately, Travis CI have PhantomJS pre installed on their virtual machine. So to make the whole thing work, I just need to plugin phantomjs into my test.</p>

<p>At the beginning, it&rsquo;s confused me when I found phantomjs is not coded with JavaScript (but C++), nor it&rsquo;s a node module. I was mistakenly thought that it&rsquo;s node implementation of browser, it can be npm installed. It turns out that it doesn&rsquo;t have much to do with nodejs. They are completely two different environment. I was trying to try the simple code on the doc, but it just not works.</p>

<p>After digging a while, I found that to make phantomjs working in node, I need to instal a bridge to make communicate, which is node module. With the bridge, I can create a phantomjs instance, then create a page instance, then open a url. After I get the response, I evaluate a piece of JavaScript function to get what we want on the page. I just typing something in the browser console and expecting something coming bac. Another interesting thing is, we I run the test, I can see the server response in my node terminal, which also include those assets request. This also proved that phantomjs is a <code>real</code> browser. At this point, I get everything I need.</p>

<p>I pick up the most used (or most famous) test tool, mocha and chai to construct the test case. Soon I found that the assert need to be async. It need to assert after the request is done. Mocha provide a very nice way to achieve, simply call the done() function after asynchronously  assert. A very nice thing about phantomjs here is that, one of my request is based on the ajax call on the page. As long as I set a few seconds timeout to wait for the request is done, test is totally working!</p>

<p>When I try to intentionally fail the test, gotcha occur. When I fail the first test, the rest tests all get timeouted error. It wired, since if one failed, the test should show that they should show, either success or fail, why it&rsquo;s a timeout error? It turns out that, when a async test failed, the assert will throw an error. So the following done() function will never run, which make the rest tests timeout. The solution is to wrap a try catch to assert and done, and call done again in the catch with e as params. So when assert failed, done will still get called.</p>

<p>After all test working locally, the deployment just work out of the box. Travis will automatically run <code>npm test</code> if there is one in the package.json. So I send a pr, all build and test start running automatically. After a while, pass all green. yay!</p>

<p><img src="http://gxding.com/images/travis-pass.png" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[做热干面]]></title>
    <link href="http://gxding.com/blog/2015/03/01/zuo-re-gan-mian/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-01T12:40:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://gxding.com/blog/2015/03/01/zuo-re-gan-mian</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>在上次非常成功地做了一次热干面之后，今天我又做了一次，依然非常成功，并且简化了一些步骤。作为程序员，经过了两次的重复，自然而然地就想到了抽象出一个可以重复使用的菜谱来，让以后都能成功得做出热干面，而不是靠感觉。</p>

<h3>需要准备的材料，超市一般都能买到：</h3>

<p>辣椒，榨菜，生抽，老抽，麻油，蒜，面条，葱，芝麻酱，芝麻，胡椒，油</p>

<p><img src="http://gxding.com/images/re_gan_mian/IMG_2286.JPG" width="180" />
<img src="http://gxding.com/images/re_gan_mian/IMG_2287.JPG" width="180" />
<img src="http://gxding.com/images/re_gan_mian/IMG_2288.JPG" width="180" />
<img src="http://gxding.com/images/re_gan_mian/IMG_2289.JPG" width="180" />
<img src="http://gxding.com/images/re_gan_mian/IMG_2290.JPG" width="180" />
<img src="http://gxding.com/images/re_gan_mian/IMG_2291.JPG" width="180" />
<img src="http://gxding.com/images/re_gan_mian/IMG_2292.JPG" width="180" />
<img src="http://gxding.com/images/re_gan_mian/IMG_2293.JPG" width="180" />
<img src="http://gxding.com/images/re_gan_mian/IMG_2294.JPG" width="180" />
<img src="http://gxding.com/images/re_gan_mian/IMG_2295.JPG" width="180" />
<img src="http://gxding.com/images/re_gan_mian/IMG_2296.JPG" width="180" />
<img src="http://gxding.com/images/re_gan_mian/IMG_2297.JPG" width="180" /></p>

<h3>步骤</h3>

<p>（注：下面是两碗的量；一勺指的是正常吃饭用的铁勺；一抖指的是倒料的时候抖一下的量）</p>

<ul>
<li>剁：剁蒜，切葱，剁榨菜</li>
<li>拌酱：两勺芝麻酱，两抖生抽，一抖油，加水拌成糊</li>
<li>煮面：两人份的面，煮着差不多熟了（用嘴尝）就捞起来，放盆里用麻油拌一拌</li>
<li>煮蒜水：放点儿水（小半碗）到锅里，加蒜煮，开了就盛到小碗里。</li>
<li>捣芝麻：把两勺芝麻捣成芝麻粉，可以用冰淇淋勺子捣</li>
<li>铺料：把面盛到碗里，铺上拌好的芝麻酱，捣好的芝麻粉，煮好的蒜水，一抖胡椒，两抖生抽，一抖老抽，剁好的榨菜，葱。</li>
<li>自己拌，自己吃。</li>
</ul>


<h3>最后的样子</h3>

<p><img src="http://gxding.com/images/re_gan_mian/IMG_2285.JPG" />
<img src="http://gxding.com/images/re_gan_mian/IMG_2284.JPG" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[WeightTracking a sample iOS app with Swift]]></title>
    <link href="http://gxding.com/blog/2015/01/12/weighttracking-a-sample-ios-app-with-swift/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-12T21:48:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://gxding.com/blog/2015/01/12/weighttracking-a-sample-ios-app-with-swift</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Trying to learn somthing new. Turns out that I am try to lose weight. Qi is a iOS developer. So why not bulid a sample iOS app that can tracking my weight.</p>

<p>The requirement:
&ndash; a input field to enter weight and a optional datetime picker to chose time (default to current)
&ndash; a list that show all records that was entered.
&ndash; ablity to edit the data in case wrong input.
&ndash; diagram of change of weigth by time
&ndash; should be about to tell weigh&rsquo;s loss/gain by week/month
&ndash; auto-sync with remote storage</p>

<p>Screen:
&ndash; screen 1: input field of weight, and a button to toggle datatime picker. top right button to show changing diagram
&ndash; screen 2: changing diagram. top right button to show all record in list, click to edit
&ndash; screen 3: edit single record.</p>

<p>Development is on going. The github repo is <a href="https://github.com/Qiki/WeightTracking.">https://github.com/Qiki/WeightTracking.</a></p>

<p>To bo continued.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2015年的展望]]></title>
    <link href="http://gxding.com/blog/2015/01/03/expectation-in-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-03T14:25:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://gxding.com/blog/2015/01/03/expectation-in-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>说什么展望的确有点空，因为这些话常常说过就忘，但是我还是还是忍不住想写下来，给自己一个目标，尽管很虽，但总比什么都没有强。2014是充满惊喜的一年。有不少事儿可以说，但是我现在心情如此急切和兴奋以至于我就想马上动手开始写2015的展望。那就简单记录一下2014发生了什么事情吧。</p>

<blockquote><p>太直奔主题，差点忘了提一提现在的状态。正坐在匹兹堡的Shadyside walnut street的coffee tree咖啡馆用MacBook和sublime敲这些字儿，外面下着小雨，有点冷。刚刚从纽约和迈阿密的10天长假回来。昨天晚上打完篮球，腿有点酸。</p></blockquote>

<p>2014年最值得一提的应该是，毕业后在匹兹堡找到了一个不错的工作，在一家叫做Branding Brand的公司做mobile web开发，为零售商开发移动购物网站。从2014年4月开始了我毕业后的第一份正式工作。总体来讲，一切都很顺利。刚刚开始的时候有一些小的难关，比如不太会和老外交流，难以融入团队。好在我比较迟钝，并没有太多在在意这些，一头闷在工作上，渐渐地获得了同事的信任，再经过几次令人满意的表现，算是在公司里找到了自己的节奏，从2014的结尾开始，走上一个好的开始。</p>

<p>另外一件事情就是遇到了Qi，Qi是一个awesome的女汉子（现在正坐在我对面），公司里的iOS developer。我俩住的很近，每天一起乘公交车，渐渐就熟悉起来了，不对，应该是很快就熟悉起来了。我们俩一见如故，对事情的想法，对生活的态度，对待人的方式。我们都很乐观，积极，努力，都坚持着自己的梦想，想了解更丰富的世界，不断让自己更加出色。刚刚一起从假期远行回来，迎接无限美好的2015。</p>

<p>好了，说说2015吧，似乎有挺多要做的，最重要的事情有两件，第一是成为牛逼的developer，第二是减肥。</p>

<p>到4月就工作满一年了，回头想想在过去的6个里自己的技术水平似乎提高的并不是很高，更多是对自己已经了解的东西更加熟悉。同时，对基础的原理有了一定程度的认识，对自己的钻研能力有了一点信心，所以说这也是对于2015来说的一个好开端。所缺乏的也很明显，一方面需要更强的抽象能力，或者说重构能力，把当前的混乱的代码重新组织成为易于维护和拓展的结构，这是JavaScript和web develor往往所缺乏的，当然这也需要不断的实践和总结。所以这也自然的到了第二方面，更多和更广的实践，配合看书总结实践的经验。</p>

<p>其实就在最近，产生好几个不错的项目想法，第一个是类似于私人助手的项目，类似于siri但是更加personal，在自己的家里通过语音进行交流，可以自定义命令，比如天气，设闹钟，记录想法，更加大胆的，开关电视，拍照录视频，接入api等等。这个项目应该会非常有意思，并且给人很大想象空间。实现起来也不回太难，在家里设置好语音输入和输出点，加上googl的语音识别api就能好方便的设置好几条有用的命令，后面的任务就是简单的堆集功能了。当然过程中应该也会有一些难点，特别是硬件方面，但应该都在可以解决的范围内。</p>

<p>第二个项目是code style formatter，项目的的出发是公司里代码缺乏code style上的一致性，我们虽然有code style，但由于code style之前代码太多而且没有人来整理，依然后大量的代码是不一致的。当然这些工作也可以是手动的一行行改，但developer的本能不允许我做这样的事。于是我自然的就想到了开发一个code formatter来自己动修复这些code style。目前有一个开源的esformatter项目用来做这样的事情，并且可以自定义规则，但我们更想修复一些convention的规则，这些规则是code style不包括的，比如requium的callback应该是error, response, body。这会是一个一个比较有挑战的项目，应为它涉及到编程语言的parser方面的知识，我并不熟悉，也没有学过编译器之类的课程。不过我相信通过这个项目，我对JavaScrpt的了解会有一些提升。</p>

<p>我一直喜欢UI方面的东西，并且移动平台上的UI设计与实现更有挑战和更多的施展空间，所以我还希望能实现一套自己的UI组件库，用到一些新的技术来练练手，比如web component，ES6，同时学习一些市面上牛逼的UI组件的设计思想。重复多造些轮子，比如重新实现一些基础组件，module loader，utility library (dom, ajax)，使用更多的abstraction layer和design pattern。</p>

<p>另外如果能接触一下其他的平台，可能会学到更多的技术思想。可以用swift写一些iOS小程序，用Rust来熟悉底层系统方面的知识。</p>

<p>看到过Vczh以前的一片文章，说经过大量实践后看书才后效果。经过一些项目实践后，看书就成了下一个目标，特别是设计模式方面的，另外编译原理，算法，操作系统也是对能力的提高有很大帮助。说道Vzch，他的“如何设计一门语言”也是很值得好好消化一下的。</p>

<p>这么多技术方面的拉练基本上已经差不多能够填满我的2015了。</p>

<p>另外一个同等重要的目标就是减肥了，其实减肥不光是变瘦，也意味着更好和健康的身体。自从工作开始，我就越来越胖了，体重的最高记录一次次被刷新，每天坐在椅子上一天下来都能感受到肚子上的脂肪堆积不下了。打起篮球来跑也跑不动，跳也跳不起，里从前的状态越来越远。减肥真的是一个很难的事情，它的难度对于我来说甚至超越了“变成牛逼的developer”，我必须在控制自己的饮食，保持不断的运动，而且是在每天花费很大精力在工作的业余。这需要我在疲惫的时候，依然保持强大的毅力，抵御住懒惰与饥饿的诱惑。还需要重新调整自己的作息规律，以及工作的节奏，以保证自己能够科学的降低体重（相对于无节制节食与运动，不顾减肥的副作用），目前的体重估计是95公斤，希望能在年底降到80公斤。</p>

<p>写着写着就不知道该怎么收尾了，我觉得好像该说说“我一定会实现的！”这样的话里激励激励自己，但是根据对自己过往经历的来看，我真的对自己的毅力缺乏信心，我也不知如何是好，只能期待自己能控制住自己，不断把自己往前push，毕竟这些确实是我想做的事情，也是应该做的事情。我想在这个时候，能不能把自己的目标实现，可能这才是区分人的地方吧，计划和设想每个人都会做，真正能付出实践的才是优秀的人。所有不用多说，行动吧。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two months on working]]></title>
    <link href="http://gxding.com/blog/2014/06/15/two-months-on-working/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-15T10:11:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://gxding.com/blog/2014/06/15/two-months-on-working</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>How is the work itself</h2>

<p>总体来说，这是一个Awesome的，让我和别人都感到幸运的工作。公司的状况感觉上非常好，在移动电子商务平台市场占有率号称是全美第一，每天感觉新的项目不断的启动，每周都有新的项目上线。整个公司的人员配置也很完备，技术开发人员占全部的员工的一半，数据分析团队也占了很大的部分，设计，产品，运维，会计，行政，管理层都有明确的分工，说明公司已经非常的完善稳定。前端组一共有二十人左右，但由于项目基本是在项目组里进行，所有我跟他们平时的交流不多，就是在第一次前端组的会上见过一面，后面也没有在开过类似的会了。前端组的老大是一个呆萌的胖子，平时很少见到他，他好像也不怎么管我们，所以加了面也没啥好聊的。前几天前端组又聚了一次，在新版Frontend的发布会上，Frontend是公司内部的前端框架，由Architecture组的人写的，狗也参加的这次发布会还是出现了不少让人起哄的场面。总之技术组给人的感觉还是非常棒的，尽管交流不多，然能看出大部分都对技术很有热情，不时能听到他们讨论有Web Component，ES6这类时髦词汇。每天都在打交道的人是项目组的同事，项目组在公司被称为Pod，我们组叫Human Center Pod，有三个前端工程师，两个后端工程师，一个项目工程师（项目经理），一个产品经理。三个前端中，一个senior，一个junior，还有一个new hire是我。七个人除了senior前端，其他都在二十来岁，跟我年龄差不多，或者比我再大一点。我的大多数问题都会向坐在我右边的junior前端求问，他再这儿工作了半年，偏传统的设计型前端，对CSS更熟悉一些，但如果遇到JavaScript的难题的时候，或者Ember的问题，常常我就的找坐在他右边的senior前端了。尽管大家都很乐于帮助，也很耐心，但从技术的追求上，他们都达不到我会去敬仰的程度，他们的expertise更多是建立在对现有项目的熟悉上。另外一点可以看出的是，他们在技术的最佳实践上并没有更新最新的步伐，不如在debug上，他们用的还是console.log，也没有使用更加高效的dev tool的re-compile，breakpoint和profile功能，还包括ember-inspector。在遇到越困难的bug时会提高越多的工作效率。</p>

<p>除了工作，上班时他们几乎无时无刻在讲笑话。一开始我觉得听不懂可能是因为我不太熟，后来熟悉一些了能听懂了发现他们真的很会讲笑话，相比之下我的确是个无聊的人。我总是不知道该说什么怎么接话，所以我只能在哪儿傻笑，实在无解。这个时候往往就在像如果是在国内，应该不会是这样吧。</p>

<p>对面的哥们儿是项目经理，负责给我们分配任务，review和merge我们的代码，年纪跟我们差不多，但似乎已经在这里混的很熟了，经常四处开会，各种领导层来这儿跟他扯淡。哥们儿确实挺牛，聪明，工作专注，也有点傲慢。似乎他总给人感觉对方比自己笨。</p>

<p>左边的产品经理是个黑人女性，非常不典型的黑人，受过高等教育，聪明，能说会道。但对于我这个不太多话的亚洲人，她跟我交流的时候总是怪怪的显得不自然。在我的眼中，她虽然能力很强，但不是那种主导事情走向的人，她有时有自己的看法并且表现出主导场面的气势，但最后往往“略显无奈”地听从了别人的想法。不知道这是不是与她是黑人这一不可避免的事实有关，还是来自于周围技术人员在知识上对她的优势。当然了，她已经做得很好了，致使表现出了的形象与她实际的影响力有些不符。</p>

<p>两个后端开发就是我们笑话的辐射中心，他们俩的笑果都是极冷的，有时候一个笑话要过好久旁边的fe才笑出声来。照美国人说，他们就是那种super nerd，特别是其中的一位，看上去非常瘦小，带着眼镜，穿着随意得邋遢，人看起来很无聊不善交际，但能感觉到内心世界很丰富，经常能语出惊人。</p>

<p>剩下的那位就是来自中国的刚工作两个月的前端工程师，能够感觉到他的谨慎但热情，可能与他的特殊情况有关，这是他的第一份工作，还不知道如何跟同事打交道的分寸，在不知道的情况下他处于理性的选择安静，这也是他第一次试图融入美国环境，尽管来了两年，但学习中周围都是中国同学，生活在中国朋友圈中是大多数，在文化上的差异也让他选择谨慎地观察，而不是贸然地行动。尽管有不少阻力，但他保持着不错的态度，保持向周围学习，表达自己的观点，遇到问题的还算能够积极乐观的去面对。问题更多的来自于他自身，他那种积极的安静的态度不能时刻的保持，因为他毕竟不是人自然的状态，一旦久了，容易造成身心俱疲，心情糟糕，反过来影响他原先的积极乐观，从而导致一个恶心循环。这就是他目前的状态。如果我周围出现了向他这样的一位员工，我也许会主动的带着他与更多的人交流，主动询问他的意见，相信他。但现实没有那么理想化，人与人之间的关系更加微妙，少有过度的行文就会引起不必要的误会，所以人们常常选择保持一定距离，这点在美国人身上更加突出，更何况是在与一个文化差距如此之大的中国人之间。他能做的只能从自身开始，一点点的融入，改变，表达。尽可能保持好他自己的状态，相信一切会好的。</p>

<h2>About the technology we use</h2>

<p>技术的选择上，公司走得非常激进，后端使用nodejs，前端使用了ember，内部框架使用npm安装，代码使用github管理，最近甚至出了一套内部的Code Style。由于项目本身大部分是不断重复的，久而久之就自然而然地形成了一套内部框架，包括前端和后端的，还有一些ui库，整体的复杂度我不认为很高。项目库的复杂度来自于checkout部分ember的那部分代码，以及产品展示页面重js逻辑的差维护性的那部分代码，还有框架与自定义代码之间的冲突，主要来自于js，另外还有一些对过时设备的支持。最近我花了大量时间在安卓的4.1.2的原生浏览器的支持上，弄得心情特别差，因为往往追踪bug到最后，发现是android自己的bug没法解决，只能找一些丑陋的补丁。</p>

<p>非常担心的是，一直这么下去会走进一个死胡同，也许对安卓老机型的bug有了更多的了解，但花了大量时间在那些毫无意义的bug上，让自己精疲力尽，又限制了自己的知识广度，更糟糕的是把自己困在了一个孤岛上，阻断了与周围人的交流的可能性。</p>

<h2>Problem now after two months</h2>

<p>问题很多，其中最大的问题应该是，经过了两个月的磨合，感觉自己仿佛失去目标，也失去追逐目标的动力。值得庆幸的是我在这里还没忘记再问自己，目标是什么？我觉得第一，成为一位牛逼的前端工程师，甚至是一位牛逼的技术人员。第二，增加自己在人群中的影响力。第三，找个女朋友。</p>

<p>三个目标来自于三个问题，第一个技术问题显而易见，自己的技术水平太过于表面，不管是HTML，CSS还是JavaScript都没有深入到技术内部，仅仅停留在应用层面。对于HTML，我只知道它的Tag有哪些，在什么时候使用什么样的Tag，但我不准确的说出HTML的语义化是什么，HTML的DOM解析是如果进行的，HTML5的api有哪些，HTML的template是如何compile的，这些都需要对HTML有更深的了解。</p>

<p>CSS可能是我比较熟悉的，但我对它的熟悉程度也就停留在对一些hack和CSS3的使用上，深入的了解需要解决的问题是，CSS的选择器该如何设计，模块化CSS，CSS的性能问题（特别是页面的reflow和repaint），如何写出高质量的CSS，移动设备的优化，跨设备的支持。</p>

<p>JavaScript可能是最复杂的，我在上面花的时间也最多，但依然感觉自己没有掌握这门语言。问题在于对JavaScript的方法和对象的继承机制没有充分理解，导致在很多代码复用问题上显得无从下手。对JavaScript的事件机制还不是很清楚，对于事件的注册，代理，触发，时间循环还不是非常清楚。JavaScript的一些常用的模式感觉有些懵懵懂懂，特别是常用observor模式，在model-view的绑定经常使用，但对其背后的机制还不是很清楚。UI组件的开发中要注意哪些问题。框架开发要注意哪些问题。Ember的充分理解。JavaScript的高级应用，包括动态编译，Test，安全，WebSocket，Promise，ES6的新特性等问题。同时还需要对平台的理解，例如浏览器的原理，网络加载的步骤，页面渲染的步骤，浏览器缓存，异步同步多线程。此外还需对常用的工具要清楚，比如commend line，linux，test framework, dev tool, profiling, jquery core。</p>

<p>如果对以上都有比较深的理解，仅仅是成为了一个资深的前端工程师。要成为牛逼的技术人员，还需要涉猎更广的技术，首先是服务器端，需要知道后端开发的通用问题，例如扩展性，复用性，可维护型。使用算法提供程序的效率。服务器配置，数据库优化，多线程的机制，并行处理，操作系统，网络协议。还需要涉猎其他平台比如ios和Android开发。优秀的技术人员还需要懂得如何让更多人的人合作开发大型的项目，团队建设，版本控制。</p>

<p>这么多看起来似乎要一下子都学会有点不切实际，但考虑到自己的职业生涯还有四十年，我想应该会在十年之内达到的把。所有首先在两年内成为一名出色的前端工程师，在五年内达到一名优秀的技术专家，在十年内成为一名合格的技术主管。</p>

<p>第二个目标是增加自己的影响力，现在很大的一个问题就是在公司里我很难找到自己的存在感。</p>

<h2>How to solve these problems</h2>

<h2>What is the big direction I am facing</h2>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Job findings in recent months]]></title>
    <link href="http://gxding.com/blog/2014/04/08/thoughts-about-job-finding-in-recent-months/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-08T15:05:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://gxding.com/blog/2014/04/08/thoughts-about-job-finding-in-recent-months</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been looking for jobs in about last 4 months since I graduated in Dec last year. Lots of things happened, both happy and unhappy thing among them. Now I am waiting for the result of my last opportunity. If negative, I most likely go back to China. So today I wanna write something about my story in last 4 months.</p>

<p>Why today? because I was happened to be a fitting mood for writing. In last four months, I was very rushed and focusing in learning knowledges and preparing for interviews. After finished the interview with Tencent, now everything need to do is waiting. And it is very fortunate that I am in a very positive, or happy status, at most of time. Negative energy first came from the job at Pitt.</p>

<h2>job at Pitt</h2>

<p>On Dec 2013, weeks before graduating, coming back from the sadness of breaking up, I re-gain the idea of finding a job in the state and sent an email to a professor I collaborated in the second semester. He used to express the willingness to employ me as stuff or researcher at the end of that co-working by telling me to contact him when leaving Pittsburgh. Couple of minutes after my email was sent, he reply me with positive attitude, which made me very delighted. When people ask about doing after graduate, I once made everyone (include myself) believe that I will work as a stuff in Pitt. However, thing was getting worse by delaying again and again. First professor told he needed weeks to get back from Prague. After back, he needed weeks to clear up his remaining works. After that, he needed to weeks to wait for meeting schedule with those higher person in charge of employment. And then meet was re-schedule two times. I was totally disappointed at that time. I express my disappointment but still keep pushing. At last, it end up with the professor not replying my email. I feel like abandoned.</p>

<h2>Start late</h2>

<p>During the contact with the professor, I naively believe that I was sure to get the job, so essentially I did not try to find other jobs. After messing up for nearly one and half months, I started my real job hunting. I picked up my CV and sent to as many as I can. (lately found it just far from enough). At the beginning I pinned most of targets to Silicon Valley. Among them are most big companies and few startups. At the same time, I also apply for some local tech company at Pittsburgh, including GE healthcare and some on Linkedin. BTW, I never get any real interview from Linkedin. Linkedin looks so ugly and low taste, but everyone finding jobs need to use it. So I cannot help but hate it very much. Ok, that&rsquo;s enough. With weeks of waiting, I continually receive rejection email and no response. Someday at library, etlds ask me if I wanna apply for Branding Brand, a local startup building mobile app and web, which also is my last opportunity here in the state.</p>

<h2>Story of Branding Brand</h2>

<p>The story of BB is also kinda long. I apply for the job very early and did have been contacted by hr. I was appointed for a phone interview for a front-end development position. I was very excited at that moment, because it is the first interview after months waiting. I made a very hardcore preparation for a week by going through a every question on the front end interview question github <a href="https://github.com/darcyclarke/Front-end-Developer-Interview-Questions">repo</a>. And of course, the interview went very well. However, the hr told me that they are in a &ldquo;hiring freeze&rdquo;. I guess because they wanna sync with the pitt career fair. So I wait for another three week for that job fair. And bad thing happened, hr told me that the front end position was probably filled. I then ask for another position, web development, which turns out still hiring. So I was appointed for another phone interview a week later. (oh, why not just onsite&hellip;) Phone passed and a week later finally onsite interview. Onsite is good but the manager is not available. Another week passed, and another onsite scheduled&hellip; Finally onsite was finally done and it was already April 3. Then it is now that I am waiting for the final offer.</p>

<h2>Little episode of Qualaris</h2>

<p>During the BB interview, I also took another company&rsquo;s interview. It is a very starting startup at Pittsburgh Forbes Ave named Qualaris and only four people, two developer, one research guy and one business guy. They are doing healthcare with web app. I meet this company on the official website onf Ember.js. There is a meet-up link to Pittsburgh&rsquo;s meet-up of Ember.js. I found one of the developer of the company. Then I check their website and they are looking for front-end developer. I applied for it and get a phone interview in weeks, which is beyond my expectation. I was doing not bad in the phone interview. Then weeks later a onsite interview with two developer. I consider myself a already qualified web developer. So their question cannot beat me in most case. Plus I have prepared for the interview for several weeks. So the tech interview was also good. Finally I met their two non-tech guys a week later. Their question are more focused on behavior questions. This make me not as good as those questions, but I am not bad at express myself. After all I am apply for a tech position and I met some problems and had experiences during project development. So I never out of words. Everything went well but the problem comes from them. They prefer me to make a internship first at summer, then decide to give a full offer. Well that is a little hard for me to accept. The contact is still on hold. I guess we are both not in a hurry.</p>

<h2>Now what</h2>

<p>My last day of the OPT three-month window is April 23. I just had the interview with Tencent yesterday. It result kinda okay and they are waiting me to take next onsite in Shenzhen when I come back to China. So it is pretty simple. If I get the offer from BB, I stay. If not, go back to China and start a another new plan.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A wandering on CSS3]]></title>
    <link href="http://gxding.com/blog/2014/02/17/a-wandering-on-css3/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-17T13:19:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://gxding.com/blog/2014/02/17/a-wandering-on-css3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>CSS3 sounds like new tech, but it has been around for years with a increasing adoption on main browsers. I have been using CSS for years, but mostly using those main features, or triditional CSS2 features like position, styling, flaoting, etc, and a little bit decorating CSS3 features like border-radius, and box-shadow. CSS is not difficult, and when I think I have master the basic, I stop exploring those new features and believe that they are still on the way on browser compatbility.</p>

<p>Recently front end technique is envolving so fast that experimental CSS3 things now become practical. Also due to the face that I have preparing for the front end job interview, I am going to make a wandering on these new features of CSS3.</p>

<h3>Decoration</h3>

<h4>box-shadow, border-radius, opacity</h4>

<p>Most common used CSS3 features, and they are very well supported by modern browsers. <code>box-shadow</code> make shadow very easy in web pages. There are several paramaters to precisely control shadows, color, offset, blur, speard and inner/outter. It is often use in popup, dropdown. It is already been vendor-prefix freed on my just look on google plus sharing popup. <code>border-radius</code> is a interesting one. It used to be a lot of round coner hack out there. Like background image replacing, pixel mimicing. And I used to get excieted by there hacks. But now, they all gone by the missive adoption of <code>border-radius</code>. It sample to use. We can control four corner by four radius parameters. <code>opacity</code> is intiative that it control the trnasperency of a element with a percentage value, which is very useful in styling, and has no side effect.</p>

<h3>Flexbox and layout</h3>

<p>I heard <code>flexbox</code> very early, with the phrase that it is the most wanted feature in CSS3. From my recent learning, it is used for layout, which is one of the most discuessed topic in css layout. There used to be 3 main layout methods on the market. Table is the note ancient. It put elements into a big table, arrange them by tr, td. It is sample but it not flexible. If we want complex layout, the markup will be massed. Second is using float. It is massively adopted. Elements is arranged horizontally by fix the width and float them. The limitation is that Their width are fixed, or at least one of them is fixed. Besides, it need some tricky way to clear these float. Third is using absolut position to control layout. The advantage is that they are very easy to control. It is more like drawing, rather than arranging. The drawback is that the main flow is breaked. The normal element flow is breaked, which make the layout less extendable.</p>

<p>Here comes the flexbox, it natually arrange the element horizontally in the flex contianer, or vertically. In the flex box container, it is very configrable to layout elements, not matter by horizontal, vertical, alignment, centering, evenly seperated, growing differently, or by custom order. It is like a new box flowing model that completely independent on normal box flow. So the flow item will not be affected by <code>float</code>, <code>clean</code> and <code>vertical-align</code>.</p>

<p>Another things need to be mentioned about layout is Grid system. Grid system is not a native css feature, but a third-party position framework that arrange elements on the page, by specifing a pre-defined class. It is suggested a optimal solution for large scaled page layout. From my personal usage of Bootstrap grid system, I feel it less flexible, but more consistent cross multi-pages. Also by grid system it is easy to implement an integrated responsive solutions.</p>

<h3>Animation</h3>

<h4>transition, animation</h4>

<p>Animation is good feature to make some easy animation. It is fairly sample to use and, more importantly, rendered by GPU, which means more smooth animation. There are two type of animation, transition and animation. Transition is simpler. It is a property of one element that indication some change of property should be gradually made. For example, element&rsquo;s width is changed by hovering. The width will change gradually. Change can only be applied to a set of properties like height/width, opacity, color, padding, margin, border, left/top. Properties that could be changed gradually. These change may triggered by a lot of event, hover, click, media-query, and javascript add class. Some parameter can also be added, like duration, delay, ease/linear, infinite.</p>

<p>Animation is little different. In order to make a animation. We first need to define an keyframe, which is defined by a bunch of properties in a period property. from <code>from</code> to <code>to</code>, or from <code>0%</code> to <code>50%</code> to <code>100%</code>. With keyframe defined, it can be assign to element by animation property, with a bunch of parameters like delay, duration, ease/linear, alternate, infinite to indicate that animation.</p>

<p>Another property is necessary to mention here, which is transform. I used to confuse it with transition. May because they looks like or they are always used together. So transform is just about four things: translate, scale, rotate, skew, and something matrix or 3d stuff. It can change an element&rsquo;s position, scale it, rotate it, and skew it.</p>

<p>TranslateZ(0) could be use as a hack to improve page render performance. It force an element into a new layer, to avoid unnecessary re-paint.</p>

<h3>Media Query</h3>

<p>Media Query is use to deal with different style for differnt devices or different screen size. With a media query, we can define a specific style for screen or print with max/min with of screen, orientation of device, use logic operator like and/or. When critiria meet, browser will load styles in it. This feature make reponsive design happened.</p>

<h3>Pseudo things</h3>

<p>Pseudo things include Pseudo class and Pseudo elements. Pseudo classes refers to most used hover, active, checked, focus. Some newly adoped CSS3 seletor like nth-child(), first-child, root. Pseudo element is more used, which is :before and :after. They literally insert a same element before/after the target element. We could set style on them to add no-sematic content-based style, like quotes, icon. They can also be used to clearfix float, by a after pseudo-element. Pseedo element must have a content property. Its content can be fill dymanically with markup attributes by <code>attr()</code>. There are a lot of interesting pseudo element usage in <a href="http://css-tricks.com/pseudo-element-roundup/">this page</a>.</p>

<ul>
<li>END &ndash;</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Something about me]]></title>
    <link href="http://gxding.com/blog/2014/02/10/something-about-me/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-10T17:37:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://gxding.com/blog/2014/02/10/something-about-me</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>this post also appear on this <a href="http://gingerbear.github.io/about">about page</a></p></blockquote>

<p>I am new-graduated student from University of Pittsburgh with a master degree in Information Science. I love technical stuffs. I start playing with computer at a fairly young age at about 10, which is specially young in a ordinary teacher family in China. My first OS was windows 98 on TCL desktop with a Celeron CPU. My first internet connection is <a href="http://www.eastday.com/">eastday.com</a>. I still cannot forget that existment. Fellowing technical move on the internet now is my daily routine.</p>

<p>My specific area is front-end development. I love playing with JavaScript, HTML and CSS. My first expose to font end stuff is in middle school around 2003, where we were guided by teacher to add a small piece of JavaScript to a HTML page in Dreamweaver, that could make an bunch of fancy stars flying around the mouse. I was shocked by that an have nothing to figure out that magic code.</p>

<p>During my undergraduate 4 years, I formally start learn programming. It was completely a stuggling experience because nobody was guiding me. I mess around with C, asp, Java, C#, .Net and finally PHP. It is a little bit embaressing to say that I love PHP. But at that time I find PHP so easy to understand and so flexiable to do what I want. With PHP, I built a CMS with two of my best friends <a href="http://www.weibo.com/xluo0209">Sean Luo</a> and <a href="http://www.weibo.com/appleet">Ivy Liu</a>. Now I still consider it a great work.</p>

<p>From the begining I feel myself love visual things. I hate reading when I was at a fairly big. I love drawing and watching. I can tell what is beauty and what is not. I also like programming. Then font-end development naturally come to my things to do. I start focusing my tech area to front-end from last two years since my intern at Cisco China RD center. My role is web developing. My works was appreciated by my colleagues and manager for it nice looking, good usibility. At that time, I start to learn JavaScript in deep level by reading <a href="http://www.nczonline.net/">Nicholas C. Zakas</a>&rsquo;s <a href="http://www.wrox.com/WileyCDA/WroxTitle/Professional-JavaScript-for-Web-Developers-3rd-Edition.productCd-1118222199.html">Professional JavaScript for Web Developers</a> and <a href="http://www.crockford.com/">Douglas Crockford</a>&rsquo;s <a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/9780596517748.do">JavaScript: The Good Parts</a>.</p>

<p>Now I am armed with modern font-end workflow with Mac, Sublime Text, Chrome DevTools, Git, Github, Front-end MVC, Grunt, Yeoman, Modular Pattern, etc. JavaScript I moving really fast and is becoming a super language that can do anything. More importantly, JavaScript comes with a better community that everyone is more like to open, share, help. It indeed have a lot of problem with the language itself that lots of arguments happened everyday. But argument is a good thing. It make things better. And I feel lucky that I am not get lost in the fancy tech world. In the following career that I am facing, I am pretty sure that what I should do and what I can achieve.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A plan to Hunting Job AS A TEAM (deprecated)]]></title>
    <link href="http://gxding.com/blog/2014/01/14/a-plan-to-hunting-job-as-a-team/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-14T18:13:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://gxding.com/blog/2014/01/14/a-plan-to-hunting-job-as-a-team</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Since many friends and me are trying to hunting job in the US. I realize there should be a place for us to discuss and share. I am think if I could build some thing that may be used for that. We will benefit from that tool and I will benefit from building that tool. Even some friends may join us building this tool and make it open-source.</p>

<p>Generally, this tool should have serveral parts:</p>

<ul>
<li>Coding Board</li>
<li>Discuess Board</li>
<li>Shared To-Do-List</li>
</ul>


<h2>Coding Board</h2>

<p>Most importantly, users are willing to have a place to post their coding puzzles, for asking help or for sharing good questions. The main page of coding board is a list of post, along with title, poster, participants, tags(help, good stuff), and time.</p>

<p>Clicking into a item in the list, it will go to the this puzzle page. It will show detail info of this puzzle. Next to the page, it will appended by a set of comment or answer to that puzzle. Also they could use @ sign to mention someone. (So far it is just like the github issue).</p>

<p>The editor for create new post should markdown and syntax highlights.</p>

<p>More features like assign helper to solve question and email notification.</p>

<h2>Discuess Board</h2>

<p>Users shared job info on this board. Like a good position opening. Or some interview experience sharing. Basicly, I this lit version of Coding Board. (Why not github)</p>

<h2>Shared To-Do-List</h2>

<p>I found myself can not live without a todo list. And I think it will be more powerful in incenting people to get shit done. Combining the coding board with the todo list, I kinda feel that will promote people to code more. Well, in a second thought, people may not that will to share their todo list. They are just not that enjoy making personal thing pulic to others. And they may feel guilty when they feel not finished the todo list, and don&rsquo;t want others know. So quite a few people may not share their todo list.</p>

<h2>In the End: Just use Github</h2>

<p>In the end of writing this post, I convinced myself not to build a customed tool specifically for this thing. It cost me too much, and just not gain too much, and people won&rsquo;t get too much better from this tool. Github is pretty well builted to fit most of the requirement. So why just make a repo, set a set of rules, and let them to join.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A phone number matching regular expression]]></title>
    <link href="http://gxding.com/blog/2014/01/10/a-phone-number-matching-regular-expression/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-10T16:11:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://gxding.com/blog/2014/01/10/a-phone-number-matching-regular-expression</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I used to void learning regular expression, because they looks too dry to digest. And in most case when I wanna use them, I can find existing ones on the web. But there are always a shadow in my mind that it is important. The shadow forms from when I found a lot of JavaScript books spending a whole chapter introducing Regular Expression. Weeks ago when I was reading Jeff Atwood&rsquo;s <em>Effective Programming: More Than Writing Code</em>, I read a chapter talking about phone screen. It point out five main part in phone screen.</p>

<ul>
<li>Coding</li>
<li>OO Programming</li>
<li>Scripting and Regular Expression</li>
<li>Data Structure</li>
<li>Bits and Bytes</li>
</ul>


<p>The <strong>Regular Expression</strong> hits me, and make me starting learn it. After reading the recommanded <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/JavaScript/Guide/Regular_Expressions?redirectlocale=en-US&amp;redirectslug=JavaScript%2FGuide%2FRegular_Expressions">MDN Article</a> and a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EkluES9Rvak">video</a> presented by Lea Verou, I start to do the sample task on Jeff&rsquo;s book about Regular Expression.</p>

<h3>A phone number match</h3>

<p>Two kinds of phone should be matched: (123)-321-4321 and 123-321-4321.</p>

<p>First, the method I use is</p>

<pre><code>Regex.test(String)
</code></pre>

<p>it will return ture if match, false if not.</p>

<p>Let&rsquo;s do the first case. a &ldquo;(&rdquo; at the begining, so /(/. Then three number and a &ldquo;}&rdquo;, so /(\d{3})/. Then just &ldquo;&ndash;&rdquo; and three and four numbers, so</p>

<pre><code>/\(\d{3}\)-\d{3}-\d{4}/.
</code></pre>

<p>In the second case, there is not &ldquo;(&rdquo;. So &ldquo;(&rdquo; should occure once or not, so add a &ldquo;?&rdquo;.</p>

<pre><code>/\(?\d{3}\)?-\d{3}-\d{4}/.
</code></pre>

<p>However there is a false positive for something like 123)-321-4321. The solution is make it occur for both &ldquo;(&rdquo; and &ldquo;)&rdquo;, OR neither of them. so</p>

<pre><code>/((\d{3})|(\(\d{3}\)))-\d{3}-\d{4}/
</code></pre>

<p>Everyone told me how powerful Regular Expressiuon is, so I guess there are much more for me to discover.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[CS2510: Project 2 - MiniGoogle Final Report]]></title>
    <link href="http://gxding.com/blog/2013/12/17/cs2510-project-2-minigoogle-final-report/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-17T16:42:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://gxding.com/blog/2013/12/17/cs2510-project-2-minigoogle-final-report</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>CS2510: Project 2 &ndash; MiniGoogle Final Report</p>

<h5>Guanxiong Ding (gud7)</h5>

<p>12/17/2013</p>

<h2>General Workflow</h2>

<h4>Indexing workflow</h4>

<ul>
<li>client send the documents to minigoogle server</li>
<li>mingoogle server dispatch socket connections to worker by fork a process</li>
<li>worker lookup mappers and reducers</li>
<li>worker split the file and send to ma ppers</li>
<li>each mapper count word for its split</li>
<li>mapper partition the word count result and send to reducer</li>
<li>reducer aggregate the result and append to master index files</li>
</ul>


<h4>Querying workflow</h4>

<ul>
<li>client send keywords to minigoogle server</li>
<li>mingoogle server dispatch socket connections to worker by fork a process</li>
<li>worker lookup mappers and reducers</li>
<li>worker send each keyword to each mapper</li>
<li>each mapper get a set of document &ndash; occurrence pairs by the keyword</li>
<li>mapper send result set to reducer</li>
<li>reducer gather all sets from mappers and calculate the total occurrence</li>
<li>reducer sort the document by total occurrence and send back to client</li>
</ul>


<h2>Client</h2>

<p>It is a program on local machine. It can be runned by user on command line along with parameters. client will first lookup the naming server to find the address of mini-google, then request for a socket connection and then send index/query request to it with connection and then waiting for response.</p>

<h3>Mini-google</h3>

<p>First it will create a socket and binding with the address and port number, then listen() in a infinite loop. When receiving a request from client, it create a new process regarding to request type (index/query) to handle the request. After that, server will keeping listening for other requests.</p>

<h3>Worker</h3>

<p>Worker is the critical part of the whole work. It holds the connection with client and send result back to client if all mappers and reducers have done their work. It will split the file by the number of available mapper it got from name server. After file splitted, it will send each split to each mapper by a set of parameters</p>

<ul>
<li>split file name</li>
<li>document name</li>
<li>number of mappers // to let reducer know when to start reducing</li>
<li>address and ports of all reducers</li>
</ul>


<p>and then waiting for their response by holding connection on multi-threads. If all mappers response work done, it will send message to client and close the connection.</p>

<h3>Mapper helper</h3>

<p>Before working, it will register on name server when start running, with it address, port and type, which is &ldquo;mapper&rdquo;.</p>

<p>Mapper first do the word counting and combining on it splits by shell script using tr, sed, awk, uniq, sort. and then do partition on the map result, by the number of reducers. It do partition not by lines, but by alphabetic. Meaning if number of reducers is 2, result will be partition to two files, one with terms from [a-m], one with terms from [n-z], which refers to the step of shuffle. Then sent each partition to each reducer and waiting for their response by holding connection on multi-threads. If all reducers response work done, it will send message to worker and close the connection.</p>

<h3>Reducer helper</h3>

<p>Before working, it will register on name server when start running, with it address, port and type, which is &ldquo;reducer&rdquo;.</p>

<p>Reducer first get the number of mappers. By this number, it will know how many mapper it have to wait. After it received all data from mapper, it will start to aggregate the mapper by shell script with awk. Then it will start 5 thread to merge result to master index. When all thread done their job. Reducer will send message back to mapper that its work done.</p>

<h3>Name Server</h3>

<p>Naming server establish sockets and keep waiting for connection. It support two type of request,register and request. Register will store address, port, server type. Lookup will will send back a set of address, port and server type by server type and number. For example, get 5 mappers, or get 3 reducers.</p>

<h3>Master index</h3>

<p>In this project, name index is separated alphabetically in 26 files for each letter. The advantage is that they could be better paralleled in indexing and querying with less concern on blocking issues.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some thoughts one day after graduate]]></title>
    <link href="http://gxding.com/blog/2013/12/14/some-thoughts-one-day-after-graduate/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-14T23:47:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://gxding.com/blog/2013/12/14/some-thoughts-one-day-after-graduate</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Now is day one after graduate. In fact I have to do my operating system project now, I too much thought are stoping me. So I decide to do project tommorrow and write all these thoughts down. Ok, use Chinese.</p>

<h2>莫扎特的Clarinet Concerto In A, K.622: 2. Adagio</h2>

<p>我正在反复听莫扎特的(Clarinet Concerto In A, K.622: 2. Adagio)[<a href="http://www.xiami.com/song/1770385763?spm=a1z1s.6659513.0.0.0555RH">http://www.xiami.com/song/1770385763?spm=a1z1s.6659513.0.0.0555RH</a>]，这首曲子能让人沉静下来能想想自己的事情。第一次听是在一个莫扎特的纪录片的片头曲听到，当时一听到那个单簧管吹出的旋律就很感动。</p>

<h2>毕业中</h2>

<h3>甘同学的包</h3>

<p>说说昨晚的一个事儿。昨天晚上与甘同学小聚，因为他要就要去加州了，月黑风高的去了匹兹堡市中心逛了逛聊了聊，回来的时候已经很晚了（或者说很早了，因为是早上六点），迷迷糊糊到了家马上就睡了，刚睡一会收到个电话说他包找不到了，里面有个两千多刀的单反，问我看看记不记得放哪儿了，我起来看了看包，发现是我自己包（恰好跟他的包除了颜色都是一样的），然后去门外看了看下车的地方也没有。我告诉他可能是放到原来的车里地上了，但他手机又没电了，钥匙在那包里也回不去。那个焦急的情景，我很能体会。中间他没有办法去买了个充电器去咖啡店充了电，又租了车去了躺路过的地方找，找不到，又打了911，甚至直接下单买了一台新的单反。到了早上我又收到了电话问我再确定一下路上有没有，尽管我很确定但还是去看了看，依旧什么都没有。我回到了房间坐再床上睡了，突然看到了我椅子下还有个包，就是他的包…… 看来是我昨晚下车的时候顺手把他的包当成我的包就直接拿走了，但是我完全不记得了。这事儿我感到十分抱歉，自己的一个犯傻导致他人身心具疲。</p>

<h3>学院三楼</h3>

<p>学院三楼一直是个热闹的地方，长期有邦邦同学把守，每次去那儿都挺欢乐。我平时不怎么去，直到这个学期的后半段去的比较多，一是由于图书馆人太多，位子不好找，二是跟认识的同学还能聊聊天，又是还能讨论讨论项目，运气好甚至还有免费的食物。在这段时间里也熟悉了不少新朋友，每次学习到后面就成了茶话会，大家还都听能聊的，还挺开心的。学院三楼的那个桌儿仿佛成了一个我们专业小伙伴们的据点，每天都会有小伙伴来首先将其霸占。</p>

<h3>Trees Hall</h3>

<p>打篮球的地儿，虽然比起国内的强多了，但地板还是不可避免的滑，我也不可避免的打得没有外场好。每周我都会来这里打两次球，认识了一堆小伙伴，真的有些不舍得离开。如果能找到匹兹堡大学的工作，最大的好处就是能继续在这儿打篮球。刚来的那会儿真是谁都不认识，很傻很天真的跟跟几个老黑打起半场来。后来打起全场第一次就更清华哥吵起来了（后来还是关系不错），狗腿后来把我拉近了他们的篮球队，每周二周五晚上都非常认真的在这里练联防和战术，当时的那几个在一队真的挺厉害的，甚至在trees都很难找到能打赢我们的队。首先我们的防守特别好，我们守的是联防，外线的补位非常及时，内线有狗腿的强硬防守。对手在进攻的时候除了投三分，几乎很难突破进来。在进攻端，大神的组织非常合理，他知道该怎么打，并且总能打出一些战术。我们还有生哥的三分球，以及非常好的快攻意识，我更像是个小前锋，进攻方式多是中投和三分，偶尔有一些挡拆的配合。后来对篮球最执着的狗腿回国了，大家似乎就没有当时的那种练球的劲头了，大家都有各自忙的事情，晚上来打球更多是为了消遣。我之前一直是做他们车过来，后面也逐渐的自己走过来了，渐渐跟他们也走得不是那么近了，更多的是想自己多发挥一些个人能力，因为说实话在之前强大打团队里，打球的方式非常单一，个人能力都退化了。总之这是一个值得回忆的地方，如果我留下，我想我需要去练练身体，把个人能力提上去。</p>

<h4>(待续)</h4>

<h3>加州</h3>

<h3>回国</h3>

<h3>分手</h3>

<h2>毕业后</h2>

<h3>学校工作</h3>

<h3>空闲的日子</h3>

<h3>朋友</h3>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Two Weeks using MacBook Pro 13 inch with Retina display 2013 late version]]></title>
    <link href="http://gxding.com/blog/2013/11/08/first-two-weeks-using-macbook-pro-13-inch-with-retina-display-2013-late-version/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-08T02:03:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://gxding.com/blog/2013/11/08/first-two-weeks-using-macbook-pro-13-inch-with-retina-display-2013-late-version</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I bought the new macbook pro right after the latest release of MBP on Apple&rsquo;s event. I was so existed about the new macbook pro, and I becoming more and more display my PC. There are a lot to talk about my loving on the new macbook pro, and lot of dis-lovness of my samsung PC. It&rsquo;s too late and I want to post this blog before sleep. So let me be short for the most important benefit.</p>

<p>Oh, by the way, Apple just release the Bug fix for this macbook I using, which happens to be freeze on daily usage on a large set of new users. It is quite annoying for my mac freezing in the way I am using. What&rsquo;s worse is that I make me feel unsafe to use this machine, and always feeling it&rsquo;s gonna stuck. But finally, it is fixed. No freezing after tonight&rsquo;s update.</p>

<h2>No.1 Shortcuts</h2>

<p>What really make my working with mac effective is its massive and make-sense shortcuts. With command key combined with another key, I can operate faster than using mouse and trackpad. The most I use is</p>

<ul>
<li>cmd + q for close window or tab</li>
<li>cmd + q for quick application</li>
<li>cmd + l to select the address bar in browser</li>
<li>cmd + t to open a new tab</li>
<li>cmd + left/right arrow to the begin/end of line</li>
<li>option + left/right move cursor word by word</li>
<li>cmd + shift + 4 to screenshot</li>
</ul>


<p>I believe there are even more shortcuts to boost my usage.</p>

<p>In addition, Alfred, of course, let me open application, file and directory without open folder and folder in finder. Which speed up my productivity a lot.</p>

<h2>No.2 Trackpad</h2>

<p>I have not using mouse for two weeks. The trackpad is super responsive and really magic with those gestures. The most useful one is multi-screen by four finger swipe left/right. It make good to organizing my applications when I open a lot. And four finger swipe up, to organize my my application automatically. I feel very comfortable and easier with different functional separated screens.</p>

<h2>No.3 Screen</h2>

<p>When I see an non-retina screen now, I will feel a lot blur. This screen is very precise and with great color. The display resolution is actually 1280x800, making 4 pixels to render 1 pixel. I cannot see the pixel in the screen, or I can see pixel clearly those application without retina-display optimization. I feel very comfortable coding with this screen.</p>

<h2>No.4 keyboard</h2>

<p>A lot of laptops try to make their keyboard looks like macbook&rsquo;s. But they failed to make their keyboards type like macbook&rsquo;s. This keyboard&rsquo;s type feel is neat. Each key is well separate and with a little curve in from the middle of key, which make you feel explicitly typing right on the key. And the keys&#8217; positions are well set. Make my muscle feel nature and comfortable when I am typing. My last PC&rsquo;s keys are really bad-positioned.</p>

<h2>No.5 Light</h2>

<p>I don&rsquo;t have to carry a so-heavy PC and charger to library everyday.</p>

<h2>No.6 Misc</h2>

<p>I call them miscellaneous not because they are not important, but they are not the greatest impact for me now. First is the batter life. I can working on it for a whole after without a charge. Second, good looking, yes, it looks beautiful like a art work. Then the charger, very well design. Cable can be well rolled on the charger. The port is magnetic and works for both direction.</p>

<h2>Summary</h2>

<p>The main things in mac is fast, clean and beautiful. I believe I won&rsquo;t change it in the following three years. Like the Julio, PhD Student of Peter, said, when I get the macbook (a old white plastic one), my life changed. I can feel that it is already change my life.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A User Level Light-weight Thread Scheduling Implementation ]]></title>
    <link href="http://gxding.com/blog/2013/11/01/a-light-weight-thread-scheduling-implementation/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-01T14:55:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://gxding.com/blog/2013/11/01/a-light-weight-thread-scheduling-implementation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In last three days, I was trying to the operating system course project. It is a user level light-weight thread scheduler, with semaphores dealing with concurrency problem. Frankly I never did and multi-thread programming before, not to mention a write a multi-thread scheduler in C. And of course, I didn&rsquo;t do well with the operating system course. I will talk about the course at the end of this post. I almost forgot this homework until I found it just left three for the due. So what I do is not from nothing, but from my <a href="https://github.com/cadmuxe">cadmuxe</a>&rsquo;s code. Here I am gonna explain how it works.</p>

<h2>Description and Requirement</h2>

<p>The whole requirement is <a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1oWoWm2MAQf7uEw0U8gwXLUK0ufQHAlexupOlO0o6QZTG3Z67kM7GrRFsV0a7LK1mHObatCizd_Y4_8RD/edit?usp=sharing">here</a>. In short, the scheduler have</p>

<pre><code>lwt_init(int quantum)
</code></pre>

<p>to set up the main thread, the global thread, the signal hander and thread running intervel with the a period of time as parameter (quantum).</p>

<pre><code>lwt_create(char *name, void *argv, fun_type fn)
</code></pre>

<p>to create a thread with name, argument pointer and function pointer. and run it immediatly. return thread indentifier.</p>

<pre><code>lwt_sleep(int seconds)
</code></pre>

<p>to put current thread into sleep for seconds.</p>

<pre><code>thrd_wait(lwt *t)
</code></pre>

<p>to put current thread into wait until the input thread (child thread) exit.</p>

<pre><code>smphr_create(int size)
</code></pre>

<p>to create a semaphore with a input size, and init a thread queue for waiting list.</p>

<pre><code>P(smphr *s)
</code></pre>

<p>to acquire semaphore if avaible, if not, put current thread into queue</p>

<pre><code>V(smphr *s)
</code></pre>

<p>to release semaphore, and dequeue the front thread in queue</p>

<h2>How to achieve multi-thread</h2>

<p>The idea is pretty similar with multi-processes running on a single processor. Threads are switched in a fast speed with a process, making it like they are served simultaneously. But how to make the switch? Use <em>alarm signal</em> to interrupt running thread, <em>setjmp</em> to save its running environment and <em>longjmp</em> to restore to its that environment. Here is the code :</p>

<pre><code>lwt_init() 
{
    /* ... */

    signal(SIGALRM, alarm_handler);
    ualarm(lwt_quantum, 0);

    /* ... */
}

void alarm_handler () 
{
    /* ... */

    if (setjmp(sys_t.curr-&gt;env) == 0) { // interrupted, save current thread's runing environment. if get here from longjmp(), setjmp will return no-zero
        do {
            sys_t.curr = sys_t.curr-&gt;next; // set next thread as current thread

            /* ... check state of current thread here */

        } while (sys_t.curr-&gt;state != lwt_READY);

        ualarm(sys_t.interval + sys_t.curr-&gt;prior, 0);
        longjmp(sys_t.curr-&gt;env, 1);    // after switch, continue running environment where it was saved
    }

    /* ... */
}
</code></pre>

<p>There is a serious problem here. Thread are created on main thread (actually process), so when they run, a stack will be allocated on the top of main stack. The stack will be remove if the thread run is over (returned). There is no problem if thread run one by one. But in this case, they are running simultaneously (not precisely simultaneous, but running without end of others). The result is that all these threads are using a same stack. We know that when we perform of a setjmp, env save the stack pointer of the thread. So it comes to the situation that switching will make thread go back to its stack pointer, but the content of that stack will not its content. Stack is all messed.</p>

<p>A way to solve this is to give each thread its own stack when they created. This is achieve by a statement of assembly language. Code is there:</p>

<pre><code>#ifdef _X86
__asm__("mov %0, %%esp;": :"r"(sys_t.curr-&gt;stack + lwt_STACK_SIZE) );
#else
__asm__("mov %0, %%rsp;": :"r"(sys_t.curr-&gt;stack + lwt_STACK_SIZE) );
#endif
</code></pre>

<p>I don&rsquo;t know jack about assembly language. But I was told that it move the stack pointer to a new stack.</p>

<h2>How to implement Semaphore</h2>

<p>Semaphore actually is quite sample (the reason I say this, because I thought it was hard). It is like a gate keeper having a list of available rooms. It will tell the visitor if any room available. If yes, gate keeper will allow the visitor to use the room and reduce the number of available rooms. If no, put the visiter on the waiting list.</p>

<p>If the visitor has done with the room, gate keeper will make that room available again, and give it to the first visitor on the waiting list, and sure remove him from waiting list.</p>

<p>P() is for thread to achieve the first part (check and gain semaphore), V() is for the second part (release semaphore and give to to front waiting list). Here is the code:</p>

<pre><code>typedef struct smphr_t {
    int     smphr_size;
    Queue   queue;              // queue store thread waiting for semophore
} smphr;

smphr * smphr_create(int smphr_size){
    smphr *s;
    s = malloc(sizeof(smphr));
    s-&gt;smphr_size = smphr_size;
    s-&gt;queue = CreateQueue();                   // use a queue to store waiting list
    return s;
}

void P(smphr *s){
    int left = ualarm(0, 0);                    // disable the context switch, by clear the alarm
    if(s-&gt;smphr_size &gt; 0){                      
        s-&gt;smphr_size -= 1;                     // semaphore offered
        ualarm(left, 0);                        // restore context switch
    } else {                                    // no more semaphore, blocked
        s-&gt;smphr_size -= 1;                     // TRICK! semaphore still need to be reduced one, in order to avoid fullCount getting too large. 
        sys_t.curr-&gt;state = sem_WAIT;
        Enqueue(sys_t.curr, s-&gt;queue);          // put into queue
        raise(SIGALRM);
    }
}

void V(smphr *s){
    int left = ualarm(0, 0);
    s-&gt;smphr_size += 1;                         // release semaphore
    if (!IsEmpty(s-&gt;queue)) {                   
        Front(s-&gt;queue)-&gt;state = lwt_READY;     // dequeue front and set to READY, if not empty
        Dequeue(s-&gt;queue);
    }
    ualarm(left, 0);
}
</code></pre>

<h2>Test with Producer-Consumer Problem</h2>

<p>The LWT can be tested by a classical Producer-Consumer problem. Producer produce item, Consumer consume item produced. If item buffer is full, producer should wait (producer trying to produce should be put on the waiting list) until item is consumed and buffer is not full. Consumer, similarly, should wait if item buffer is empty (put on waiting list), until item is produced and buffer is not empty.</p>

<p>So we need a fullCount Semaphore (max size of buffer) to decide if full, a emptyCount Semaphore (max size of buffer) to decide if empty and a useLock to only let one producer/consumer access to buffer at one time. Here is the code:</p>

<pre><code>void producer(){
    srand(time(NULL));  // Initializes random number generator
    int item = 0;
    while(1){        
        item = rand();
        P(emptyCount);
        P(useQueue);
        if (current &lt; N) {
            buffer[current++] = item;
        }
        V(useQueue);
        V(fullCount);
        printf("Producer: %s\tproduce: %d\te: %d\tf: %d\tSize:%d\n"
            , get_curr_name()
            , item
            , smphr_get_size(emptyCount)
            , smphr_get_size(fullCount)
            , current);
    }
}

void consumer(){
    int item = 0;
    int i = 0;
    while(i &lt; 30){ 
        P(fullCount);
        P(useQueue);
        if (current &gt; 0) {
            item = buffer[--current];
        }
        V(useQueue);
        V(emptyCount);
        printf("Consumer: %s\tconsume: %d\te: %d\tf: %d\tSize:%d\n"
            , get_curr_name()
            , item
            , smphr_get_size(emptyCount)
            , smphr_get_size(fullCount)
            , current);
        i++;
    }
}

int main(int argc, char *argv[]){
    int i,j;
    lwt *t;
    emptyCount  = smphr_create(N);
    fullCount   = smphr_create(0);
    useQueue    = smphr_create(1);

    lwt_init(QUANTUM);

    lwt_create("p1", 0, NULL, producer);  
    lwt_create("p2", 0, NULL, producer);  
    lwt_create("p3", 0, NULL, producer);  
    lwt_create("p4", 0, NULL, producer);  
    lwt_create("c1", 0, NULL, consumer);     
    t = lwt_create("c2", 0, NULL, consumer);     

    thrd_wait(t);
    printf("Two Consumers consume 30 items!\n");
    printf("Done!\n");
}
</code></pre>

<p>The full code is on <a href="https://github.com/GingerBear/LWT">github</a>. Thanks to <a href="https://github.com/cadmuxe">cadmuxe</a> and <a href="https://github.com/liyangbin">liyangbin</a> for the help.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building the IS Reader]]></title>
    <link href="http://gxding.com/blog/2013/10/28/building-the-is-reader/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-28T02:16:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://gxding.com/blog/2013/10/28/building-the-is-reader</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It has been a few weeks that I am thinking about writing a blog on the IS Reader project. In this post, I will try to answer:</p>

<ul>
<li>Why did I start the project?</li>
<li>What will the product be functioning like?</li>
<li>How did I or will I deal with it?</li>
<li>What are the design rules that I am following?</li>
</ul>


<h2>Why did I start the project?</h2>

<p>There are a lot of reasons that finally lead me to build this reader. First and most importantly, When I reading some long documents, like a book, I found myself need a sample tool that can store a pdf document online, and everytime you open it on different devices, it will restore the previous page you read. I went throught a series of search but didn&rsquo;t find a sample solution. Kindle App may work but not allow pdf uploads. Dropbox and Google Drive show pdf cross device but cannot restore the progress, no need to say annoating or sharing. Foxit reader can restore but only work locally.</p>

<p>The secend reason is that, I was happened to take an independent study with Peter&rsquo;s, our program head, phd student Julio, who took me to the ReadingCycle project. It is also a reader project, but only work for picture format books. So it is a good change to do it along with the IS Reader. (Actually IS Reader the name came with the inital of School of <em>Information Science</em>, but not limit to that.)</p>

<p>Thirdly, I am on my way finding a job, this project will be a great enhancement of my experience and CV. I will try a lot of new technologies that could be written on my CV.</p>

<p>Finally, there is no such a product on the web and it is not that hard to build, so why don&rsquo;t I create one. Maybe it will grow into a real deal.</p>

<h2>What will the product be functioning and look like?</h2>

<p>On the first thought, the product is pretty sample. I can upload pdf documents on it, read it, restore the page on other devices and continue reading. By further thinking, it should support multi-user, not just me alone. Then it should provide a certain management page that can CRUD those documents. Next, it should allow user to annotate on the document. Finally, social stuff. User can share documents, notes with each other. They can track their progross. Product can even provide some kind of stratagy that my drive user to reader more, like comparing, gamification.</p>

<p>At this moment of my typing, I am thinking the goal of the product should be to <strong>make people more like to read</strong>, or to learn, since I read for learn.</p>

<h2>How did I or will I deal with it?</h2>

<p>As I mentioned, the article should be typed several weeks ago, which means I have started working on it for several weeks (19 days since its github inital commit). I choosed all those new technology from the begining. At the begining scaffolding stage, I user Yeomen to genate a express project and a webapp (merged in the middle of developing, cover later).</p>

<p>I use pdf.js for the JavaScript-based pdf rendering. Although its rendering is a bit not that sharp on windows, it is good enough for long time reading. Not surprisingly, it renders perfectly on MacBook Pro with Retina display (need to fix the scale issue), the one I just bought, and better on mac with no-Retina than windows.</p>

<p>For the server, I use Express on Node.js, Mongoose and MongoDB for the database, Jade for the template engine. In fact, I tried to build a pure RESTful for the server, so I didn&rsquo;t use Jade at the first time. But met a lot of issues. First I came across some cross-domain issue on the cross ajax call from the client. I tried jsonp and cors to fix it. Then I didn&rsquo;t find a way to validate user session in a rapid way except cookies (I don&rsquo;t have experience with OAuth). So I gave up the RESTful option, in order for the quick shipping.</p>

<p>For the client side, most code I wrote is about the reader page. The logic is sample and old-fashion, just some event binding and ajax call, store data in the dom. What&rsquo;s new is that I try to use some new JavaScript techniques. I use event delegation of those massive event bindings. I wrap the whole reader JavaScript logic in a constructor, which construct the JavaScript by parameters, hide internal private parameters and methods, and get inited by init(); Some progress was made, but way not enough. The code is close to spaghetti, dom bindings are hard coded inside. I am extremely want to make it modular and less coupled, maybe after a big release.</p>

<p>Now, basic funcitons till making note are made. Next thing should be involved with some social, with OAuth bulid in, and books management with one-page app style (AngularJS or BackboneJS).</p>

<h2>What are the design rules that I am following?</h2>

<p>It is too late now, let me be short. For the design, 3 rules:</p>

<ul>
<li>Rule 1: As easy to use as possible</li>
<li>Rule 2: As less reading interuption as possible</li>
<li>Rule 3: As clean and sample as possible</li>
</ul>


<h2>Summary</h2>

<p>Use the most quoted facebook works:</p>

<blockquote><p>Keep Focus and Keep Shipping</p></blockquote>

<p>That is all I need to do, no need to think to far. No matter what will the product be in the future, it has a good start, namely I build it for myself use.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[主机对比总结]]></title>
    <link href="http://gxding.com/blog/2013/07/18/%25e4%25b8%25bb%25e6%259c%25ba%25e5%25af%25b9%25e6%25af%2594%25e6%2580%25bb%25e7%25bb%2593/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://gxding.com/blog/2013/07/18/%e4%b8%bb%e6%9c%ba%e5%af%b9%e6%af%94%e6%80%bb%e7%bb%93</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<strong>1. 选择虚拟主机，VPS，还是云平台？</strong>

虚拟主机，也就是Web Hosting，类似于000，与其他人共享一个OS环境。
<ul>
	<li>优点：便宜，配置方便。</li>
	<li>缺点：不稳定，速度较慢，限制多。</li>
</ul>
VPS，Virtual Private Server，在一台设备上虚拟出的多个OS环境，用户能独享一个OS。
<ul>
	<li>优点：稳定，自由（能拥有root权限），安全。</li>
	<li>缺点：需要手动安装程序，需要linux维护。</li>
</ul>
云，“如果云不是指弹性云&#8230;..那单机云就是vps&#8230;..“，“弹性云就是可以自由调整配置， 可以制作模板动态扩容/缩减， 按时按需计划，提供多节点自动的动态负载均衡” <span style="text-decoration:underline;"><a href="http://www.hostloc.com/thread-194935-1-1.html">http://www.hostloc.com/thread-194935-1-1.html</a></span>

<strong>2. AWS(云), Azure(云), Linode(VPS) 参数对比</strong>
<div>
<table width="100%" border="1" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="2">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td valign="top"></td>
<td valign="top">  AWS Free Tier</td>
<td valign="top">Azure Extra Small</td>
<td valign="top">Linode 1G</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top"><strong>RAM</strong></td>
<td valign="top">  613MB</td>
<td valign="top">768M</td>
<td valign="top">1GB</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top"><strong>CPU</strong></td>
<td valign="top">  N/A</td>
<td valign="top">shared</td>
<td valign="top">8 cores</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top"><strong>Storage</strong></td>
<td valign="top">  30G</td>
<td valign="top">20G</td>
<td valign="top">24G</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top"><strong>Database</strong></td>
<td valign="top">  20G</td>
<td valign="top">N/A</td>
<td valign="top">N/A</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top"><strong>Transfer</strong></td>
<td valign="top">  15G</td>
<td valign="top">5G free, $0.12/GB(5G-10T)</td>
<td valign="top">2T</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top"><strong>Cost</strong></td>
<td valign="top">  1-year free/ charge on demand</td>
<td valign="top">15/m</td>
<td valign="top">20/m</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top"><strong>*</strong></td>
<td valign="top">  1-year free means 750 hours CPU (<span style="text-decoration:underline;"><a href="http://python.6.x6.nabble.com/CPyUG-OT-Amazon-EC2-VS-Linode-td2730701.html">普遍反映贵</a></span>, <span style="text-decoration:underline;"><a href="http://www.quora.com/Amazon-Web-Services/How-much-does-it-cost-for-a-similar-linode-instance-on-EC2">略复杂1</a></span>, <span style="text-decoration:underline;"><a href="https://forum.linode.com/viewtopic.php?t=9885&amp;p=57731">略复杂2</a></span>)</td>
<td valign="top">Extra Small 有5Mbps 带宽限制，Small则要45/m</td>
<td valign="top">纯净Linux, 所有东西需要自己配置</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</div>
<strong>3. 方案</strong>

先使用$200的Azure的Web Site，再使用Linode的VPS，因为

1）需要快速上线，Azure的Web Site现在已经部署上线，Linode需要在命令行配置LAMP运行环境，AWS配置更加复杂。

2）开始访问量低，Azure的Shared Web Site应该能够应付，尽管性能较低。

3）Azure能够应付突发的访问量，尽管超出定额后会收费较高。

4）Linode的口碑最佳，稳定高速，简单易于维护，适合中小应用。

5）如果以后访问量巨大，可再迁移到功能更强大的AWS。

6）$200不用白不用。
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Experimental Summer Life]]></title>
    <link href="http://gxding.com/blog/2013/05/23/experimental-summer-life/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://gxding.com/blog/2013/05/23/experimental-summer-life</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[还是写中文吧。

从五月到八月，本来是打算找个地方实习的，然后再选一门课，下学期就可以part-time，但并未如愿以偿。之前与Interactive System Design这门课中的项目合作单位Department of Oral Biology in School Of Dental Medicine联系了实习，对方也给出了积极的回应，但不巧对方教授出差，等她回来后距离选课（申请CPT）的日子只有不到一周，随即她告诉我在截止日期前完成实习手续已无可能。实习便只能作罢。

然后就是自己两周低落的无所事事，每天打篮球，看季后赛，看电影，看书，生活毫无规律。心想这个四个月要是这么过，毕业找工作什么就别想了，更别谈什么梦想志向了。不在于四月有多么重要，而在于对自己管不住自己感到失望，从而失去了自信。

倔强的我于是觉得自己该做点该做的，坚持四个月，一定能改变自己。于是便有了这篇本想要英文写的文字，试验性的暑假生活。“实验性”第一是因为自己打算过一次从来没过过的暑假（可能是最后一个暑假），第二因为自己想过一种激进的生活，看看自己的level到底能到多少。

我认为自己是有天赋了，在各个方面达到远胜现在的高度。比如篮球，比如技术，比如自信，比如vision。事实并不残酷，我只是没有尽力，没有管住自己。我要证明我能能够做到。

首先是肥胖，自制力差的最直观表现。在这两周的无所事事中，体重飙升，几乎到达了90公斤，原因主要是没有控制住饮食，再加上脚伤，篮球也并没有坚持每天打。其实要减肥也很简单，生活规律，控制饮食，保持锻炼。所以在这个暑假里，我要做到日常饮食以水果，蔬菜，面包以及少量肉类为主，stay real hungary，把体重控制到75以内。每天早上坚持跑步，做力量训练，周二周五打篮球。每天一点以前睡觉，早上七点起床。

然后是学习，主要是技术上的学习。四个月的时间可以学习很多东西，但目标很明确，Google的要求是什么就学什么。下面是Google Front End Engineer的要求
<div>Minimum qualifications</div>
<div>
<ul>
	<li>BS degree in Computer Science or related field (In lieu of degree, 4 years of relevant work experience).</li>
	<li>Development experience in server-side technologies such as C/C++ and/or Java.</li>
	<li>Experience with AJAX, HTML and CSS, or Ruby, with an interest in user interface design.</li>
	<li>Web application development experience.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div>
<div>Preferred qualifications</div>
<div>
<ul>
	<li>Masters or PhD in Computer Science or related field.</li>
	<li>Significant experience developing user-facing software.</li>
	<li>Experience working on cross-browser platforms.</li>
	<li>Knowledge of UI frameworks such as XUL, Flex, and XAML.</li>
	<li>Object-oriented JavaScript skills.</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
明显不足的一点是一门Server-Side的语言，比如Java，在很多笔试题中Java也经常会使用到。

所以第一件事情是学习Java，学到什么程度，第一是写一个OOP的博客，第二是熟练使用Java写算法题。

第二重要的应该是深入了解JavaScript，对于JavaScript的语言特性，面向对象机制，模块化，主流框架，NodeJs都应该到底master的程度。学习的途径第一是看书，手上的几本书在四个月内都应奋力读完，做好读书笔记。途径二是参加开源项目，从那篇学习开源项目的文章开始看起。

第三和第四同等重要，即计算机基础知识与前端基础知识。计算机基础知识包括Linux和C语言，重读Linux和C一站式编程，了解服务器，编译器，浏览器内核的底层实现原理。第四是前端基础知识，包括CSS的深入学习，CSS3与HTML5的新特性，浏览器兼容性的知识。

第五和第六同等重要，即设计的学习与知识杂项。设计一直是我很向往的方向，但始终都处在感性的认识阶段，未来我隐约感觉到自己会走上“设计师”的道路，但开始，还是从Engineering入门会更加基础牢固，所以在暑假的闲暇时间里读一些设计方面的名著是很有益的。知识杂项就就包括了一些必要的但了解即可的知识，比如Git，不如Ruby，比如Sayanee的Vimeo，以及一些讲座。

总结成一份List，暑假每天应该这么过：

身体方面：
<ul>
	<li>7点起床，晚上1点之前睡觉</li>
	<li>早晨跑步，力量训练，周二周五晚上打篮球</li>
	<li>饮食规律，水果蔬菜为主</li>
</ul>
知识方面：
<ul>
	<li>8小时学习时间</li>
	<li>制定每月每周每日目标</li>
	<li>2小时读书</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[暑假学习第一天]]></title>
    <link href="http://gxding.com/blog/2013/05/23/%25e6%259a%2591%25e5%2581%2587%25e5%25ad%25a6%25e4%25b9%25a0%25e7%25ac%25ac%25e4%25b8%2580%25e5%25a4%25a9/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://gxding.com/blog/2013/05/23/%e6%9a%91%e5%81%87%e5%ad%a6%e4%b9%a0%e7%ac%ac%e4%b8%80%e5%a4%a9</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[积极地说，感觉还不错，虽然做的还远不够好。

由于昨天睡得晚，今天9点才起来，但早晨状态不错，并不困，简单吃了早餐和锻炼后，开始干正事儿。实际上这个时间是一天最佳的时间，所以应该花在最重要的事情上，但惰性使然，导致自己看起了vimeo的教学视频，一看就看了好多。略看了一下已知的知识，包括sublime tex, wordpress, web font。了解了一种格式语言Markdown，使用在github的readme中，通过ruby能够自动转化成HTML。还了解到了sublime text的package manager，下载的sass的代码高亮。最主要的是学习了一下SASS。

<strong>SASS最主要的是三个功能：变量，方法，循环。</strong>

使用美元符号$定义变量，可以定义统一的颜色，宽度，让CSS更容易维护。

使用@mixin定义方法，在方法体内写入复用CSS，可以传递参数，使用@include调用。这使得按钮，widget很容易实现，配合变量，使得样式的主题很容易修改。

循环的格式为
<blockquote>@for i from 1 through 9</blockquote>
缩进的内容为循环体。循环可以实现渐变的样式，但我觉得用处不大。

<strong>另外SASS的使用规则还有：</strong>
<ul>
	<li>不需要大括号，使用缩进</li>
	<li>可用用缩进加$重复利用某一元素，类似于JavaScript的with关键字</li>
	<li>一些函数darken(#ccc, 10%), lighten(#ccc, 10%)</li>
</ul>
从sass &#8211;watch产生了小想法。watch能使.sass每次有变化的时候会自动编译成.css文件，那么，做web开发的时候，每当完成某个页面的时候，当自动保存sublime text后能不能自动刷新浏览器呢？这会带来一些方便。

很快就到午饭时间了，吃了牛肉青椒番茄丁拌米线，半小时搞定。打算下午考驾照permit，开始做题，到了快两点出门结果下大雨，走了不远便打道回府。开始干“正事儿”。进入状态很慢，Java读着读着就容易走神，容易去看别的东西。看着看着觉得Java学习内容太多，太难肯，并且在web方向用的不多。并且越来越觉得Python更加适合，应用更广，更新，与web更近。回头再把Java扔到了一边开始找Python的书看，挑了不少时间结果很不明智地挑一本cookbook，鼓足一股劲开始啃了一起来，终于啃到正题了，结果发现根本就不是我需要的，都是一些细节函数的用法，没法读只能用来查。又扔到了一遍。又找了一圈要么太基础，要么太专，要么太老。我开始上网找网上的学习资料，结果看到了<a href="http://www.learnpython.org/">http://www.learnpython.org/</a> 就又鼓起劲开始学了起来，非常基础但让我熟悉其语法来了，也加上了一些小coding，很快就把基础知识过了一遍。

想尝试做几道leetcode题目但对于Java还是太不熟悉，无从下手。

就这么已经晚上11点了。最正题的JavaScript还没看。

&nbsp;

虽然没完成任务，但状态感觉还是有很大进步的，后面抓紧分配好时间，提前在google calendar上制定好时间。
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dropbox + Git 多人协作]]></title>
    <link href="http://gxding.com/blog/2013/02/13/dropbox-git-%25e5%25a4%259a%25e4%25ba%25ba%25e5%258d%258f%25e4%25bd%259c/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://gxding.com/blog/2013/02/13/dropbox-git-%e5%a4%9a%e4%ba%ba%e5%8d%8f%e4%bd%9c</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div>
<h1><strong>背景： </strong></h1>
</div>
一个人开发项目到了一半，想多拉几个人过来一起开发。
<h1><strong>使用顺序： </strong></h1>
<h2><strong>（一）我先配置好公共的repo。</strong></h2>
1. 在Dropbox上创建一个文件夹作为共享的空repo：
<pre><span style="color:#999999;"> $ cd C:/Users/Neil/Dropbox/</span>

<span style="color:#999999;"> $ mkdir Git-Repository/MyProject1.git</span>

<span style="color:#999999;"> $ cd Git-Repository/MyProject1.git</span>

<span style="color:#999999;"> $ git init --bare

</span></pre>
2.  把原来本机上项目放到到那个共享的repo里：
<pre><span style="color:#999999;"> $ cd C:/User/Neil/Projects/MyProject1</span>

<span style="color:#999999;"> $ git init</span>

<span style="color:#999999;"> $ git remote add origin C:/Users/Neil/Dropbox/Git-Repository/MyProject1.git</span>

<span style="color:#999999;"> $ git add .</span>

<span style="color:#999999;"> $ git commit -m "first commit."</span>

<span style="color:#999999;"> $ git push origin master</span></pre>
<h2></h2>
<h2><strong>（二）新加进来的开发们在本机clone一份。</strong></h2>
<span style="color:#999999;">注意：在操作git之前，先config好自己的user.name和user.email</span>

1. 创建本地目录，把Dropbox共享到的repo clone到里面。
<pre><span style="color:#999999;"> $ cd C:/User/Eric/Projects/</span>

<span style="color:#999999;"> $ git clone C:/Users/Eric/Dropbox/Share/MyProject1.git</span></pre>
<h2></h2>
<h2><strong>（三）开始日常开发。</strong></h2>
1. 获取最新的版本：
<pre><span style="color:#999999;"> $ cd C:/User/Eric/Projects/MyProject1</span>

<span style="color:#999999;"> $ git pull origin master

</span></pre>
2. 完成一个小功能后，commit一个版本到本地的repo：
<pre><span style="color:#999999;"> $ git add .</span>

<span style="color:#999999;"> $ git commit -m "comment on this commit"

</span></pre>
3. 完成一个大功能后，把本地的repo push到共享的repo里：
<pre><span style="color:#999999;"> $ git add .</span>

<span style="color:#999999;"> $ git commit -m "comment on this commit"</span>

<span style="color:#999999;"> $ git push origin master</span></pre>
<h2></h2>
<h2><strong>另外：</strong></h2>
可能会遇到冲突，因为在你pull最新版本下来之后，又有人push了更新的版本到共享repo里，而且他修改了跟你相关的代码。因此当你现在push的时候会出错，因为共享repo也不知道用他的代码好还是你的代码好。这时就git就会要求你在push之前再pull一次，并且会告诉你冲突的地方，在具体文件中会以下面这种方式体现：
<pre><span style="color:#999999;"> &lt;&lt;&lt;&lt;&lt;&lt;&lt;&lt;&lt;&lt;&lt;&lt;&lt;&lt;&lt;&lt;</span>

<span style="color:#999999;"> 我的代码</span>

<span style="color:#999999;"> ===========</span>

<span style="color:#999999;"> 他的代码</span>

<span style="color:#999999;"> &gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;</span></pre>
我需要把这段代码解决（跟他商量怎么回事儿）之后在push到共享的repo。

（完）
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[备忘ebay的一个讲座]]></title>
    <link href="http://gxding.com/blog/2013/02/13/%25e5%25a4%2587%25e5%25bf%2598ebay%25e7%259a%2584%25e4%25b8%2580%25e4%25b8%25aa%25e8%25ae%25b2%25e5%25ba%25a7/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://gxding.com/blog/2013/02/13/%e5%a4%87%e5%bf%98ebay%e7%9a%84%e4%b8%80%e4%b8%aa%e8%ae%b2%e5%ba%a7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<strong>演讲人</strong>：Brain Johnson@ebay

<strong>主题</strong>：ebay的大数据

<strong>最大印象</strong>：努力很大，投入很多，但效果一般（5% better / year）

<strong>片段</strong>：

&#8220;big is not the case, detail is.&#8221;

关于 搜索key word expansion，他讲了很多情况中是不是要把搜索关键词的相关词也纳入搜索范围，比如加s的复数。但在会出现加了s就是毫不相关的东西，例子忘了。另外，在人们搜索diary的时候，很多人想找的是吸血鬼日记，而不是笔记本。在人们搜索basketball的时候，大多数人想找的是篮球鞋，而不是篮球。我的第一影响力可以用搜索后，点击商品的类别来自动划分不同key word的expansion。

他还略过了一句话，其实也是我很想问的。那就是他说算法不重要（大概意思），数据更重要。为啥？

刚开发的时候，ebay投了几千万美元（具体忘了），结果由于所带来的改进，几个月（具体忘了）就赚回来了。看来有和无的差别是巨大的。
<div>
<div>他还分享了任务的data flow pipeline:</div>
<div>
<ul>
	<li>production</li>
	<li>behavioral item data analysisi</li>
	<li>feature generation</li>
	<li>classification prediction</li>
	<li>offline analysis</li>
	<li>human judgment</li>
	<li>a/b test</li>
</ul>
（完）

</div>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
